thebay.com 2011-12-05

# the Bay

##### 

    * ###### [How to contact the Hbc Privacy Office](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term1)

    * ###### [Frequently Asked Questions](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term2)

    * ###### [Website Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term3)

    * ###### [Hbc Rewards Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term4)

    * ###### [Hbc Credit Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term5)

    * ###### [Gift Registry Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term6)

    * ###### [Major Home Fashions Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term7)

    * ###### [Clientelling Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term8)

    * ###### [Hbc Insurance Agency Privacy Information](http://www.thebay.com/eng/customerService/PrivacyPolicy.cfm#term9)

##### Hbc is protecting your privacy

For over 335 years, Hudson's Bay Company (Hbc) has been a name that means trust in this country. We value you as our customer, and want to assure you that our 70,000 associates are committed to upholding the trust you've placed in us as Canada's oldest corporation and largest department store retailer.

Hbc's Principles for the Protection of Personal Information were created to ensure we preserve the confidentiality, accuracy and security of your personal information. These principles guide us in the collection, use, retention and disclosure of your personal information in all of our Hbc family of stores and services: the Bay, Zellers, Home Outfitters, Fields, Hbc Credit, Hbc Rewards and Hbc Insurance. 

### The information that we collect

Personal information means any information about an identifiable individual. This includes information such as your name, address, telephone number, birth date, purchase information or e-mail address. As a customer, you provide Hbc with this information in a variety of ways, such as when making a purchase, applying for an Hbc Credit Card, enrolling in our Hbc Rewards program, entering in-store contests or signing up for our Gift Registry program. In every case, Hbc adheres to strict guidelines when dealing with your personal information.

### Collecting your personal information

Hbc collects and uses personal information in connection with providing you with goods and services. When you provide Hbc with personal information, we will inform you as to why we are collecting it. Hbc obtains your consent for the collection of your personal information. In some instances, where the purpose for collection is obvious, your consent is implied. Hbc will ask for your permission to collect additional information that may be useful in serving you in the future.

### Using and disclosing your personal information

Hbc only uses and discloses your personal information for the marketing purposes identified to you when your consent to the collection of your personal information was obtained. Hbc does not provide your personal information for marketing purposes of other organizations without your consent. You can withdraw, at any time, your consent for the use of your personal information that is not required for a transaction subject to legal restrictions and upon reasonable notice to Hbc. Your information may be retained by Hbc for audit or archival purposes.

### Maintaining and safeguarding your personal information

Hbc strives to ensure that our security measures protect against loss, theft and unauthorized access, use, disclosure or modification of your personal information. Hbc limits access to your personal information to those Hbc associates who may need it for use in accordance with Hbc's established privacy principles. Hbc associates sign an annual Code of Conduct, which requires them to keep your personal information confidential and comply with our security standards. Hbc keeps your information for as long as necessary to accomplish the identified purpose and in order to serve you better. Your information is then destroyed according to legislative requirements.

### You are entitled to access your personal information

If you request access to your personal information, Hbc will respond to your request within 30 days. There is no cost for reasonable requests unless you require copies of records. Hbc will advise you of the cost, if any, prior to copying those records. Hbc may not be able to provide you with access to your personal information where the information cannot be separated from the records of others, cannot be disclosed for reasons of security or commercial confidentiality, or is protected by legal privilege.

### Hbc provides you with the answers

Hbc has established a Privacy Office and has appointed a senior executive as its Privacy Officer to ensure that everyone at Hbc complies with our Principles for the Protection of Personal Information. Hbc will investigate and respond to any questions, complaints or requests for information you may have.

### How to contact the Hbc Privacy Office

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about privacy at Hbc, or if you want to withdraw your consent for the use of your personal information, or to obtain a copy of our Principles for the Protection of Personal Information, contact the Hbc Privacy Office at: 

  * Hbc Privacy Office 
  * P.O. Box 4135 Station A 
  * Toronto, Ontario 
  * M5W 3B7 
  * 1-866-225-8251 

### Frequently Asked Questions

##### 

**1**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**What is "personal information"?**  
  
---|---|---  
| 

**A:**

| 

"Personal information" is any information about an identifiable individual. This includes information such as a person's name, address and phone number.  
  
**2**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**Do I have to give Hbc my personal information in order to conduct business with Hbc?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

There are several instances where you are required to give us your personal information for operational and/or administrative purposes. For example, we require your personal information in order to manage your Hbc Rewards account, deliver an item to you that you may have purchased, or maintain your gift registry. Giving us your personal information for these kinds of _primary_ operational purposes is necessary to obtain certain products and services from Hbc. 

However, agreeing to the use of your personal information for additional secondary marketing purposes is entirely up to you. You may contact our Privacy Office at any time to request that we not use your personal information for marketing purposes.   
  
**3**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**What are the differences between primary and secondary purposes of personal information collection?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

_Primary_ purposes are those purposes that are operational and are absolutely necessary for Hbc to be able to provide the products and/or services that you request from us. For example, a primary purpose for our collecting your address may be to ensure we can successfully deliver to your home an item you may have purchased. 

_Secondary_ purposes are any purposes that are over and above the primary/operational purposes, like sending you communications that may include notifications of sales, special events, store promotions and exclusive offers.   
  
**4**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**Will I be advised of the collection purposes prior to giving my consent?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

Yes. When you fill out an Hbc form that asks for your personal information (e.g. gift registry form, Hbc Rewards enrollment form, etc.) there is a privacy notice that outlines both our primary and secondary purposes for collecting your information.   
  
**5**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**Why is it important to keep Hbc up to date with regards to my personal information?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

Keeping your personal information as accurate and up-to-date as possible ensures that you will get the best possible information and service offerings from Hbc.   
  
**6**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**What are my opt-out choices?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

You can opt-out of receiving communications via specific contact channels. For example, you can choose to no longer receive marketing-related phone calls, but you may choose to continue receiving notification of sales and exclusive offers in the mail. However, you may not be able to restrict your communications to specific programs. Contact our Privacy Office for more details on your opt-out choices.   
  
**7**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**If I opt-out, how long will it take to stop receiving marketing materials after I contact you?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

Many will stop immediately or within days, while others may take longer.   
  
**8**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**May I review the personal information Hbc has about me? Can I obtain copies of that information?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

Yes. You can review the personal information we have about you on file by contacting our Privacy Office. There is no cost for reasonable requests for access to your personal information, but there may be a fee to supply you with copies of records. We will advise you of the fee, if any, at the time of your request.   
  
**9**

| 

**Q:**

| 

**Where can I get a copy of Hbc's Customer Privacy Brochure?**  
  
| 

**A:**

| 

There are three ways you can obtain our Hbc Privacy Brochure:  
•   Visit the customer service desks at any of the Hbc family of stores  
•   Download the PDF version of our Customer Privacy Brochure now  
•   Contact our Privacy Office:  
     **Hbc Privacy Office  
    P.O. Box 4135, Station A  
    Toronto, Ontario  
    M5W 3B7  
    Phone: 1-866-225-8251

    Email: privacy@hbc.com

**  

###   
Website Privacy Information

This website is owned and operated by Hudson's Bay Company in conjunction with its subsidiaries (including Zellers Inc.) and their affiliates (collectively referred to herein as "Hbc").

### Use of your Personal Information collected through eNewsletter Subscriptions

The information provided by you to subscribe to the Hbc eNewsletter is collected by Hudson's Bay Company and/or its affiliate Zellers Inc. (collectively, "Hbc") to deliver the Hbc eNewsletter to your email address and maintain the accuracy of your information. If you wish to unsubscribe from our eNewsletter, please click the "unsubscribe" option that appears at the bottom of every eNewsletter. If you wish to obtain more information on Hbc's Privacy Policy, please contact the Hbc Privacy Office.

### Use of your Personal Information collected through Shop.Hbc.com Membership

The information provided by you to become a Shop.Hbc.com member is collected by Hudson's Bay Company and/or its affiliate Zellers Inc. (collectively, "Hbc") to make your next online visit more convenient for you and maintain the accuracy of your information. If you wish to discontinue your Shop.Hbc.com membership, please click the "remove membership" button that appears on your Membership Services page. If you wish to obtain more information on Hbc's Privacy Policy, please please contact the Hbc Privacy Office.

### Use of your Personal Information collected through Shopping Transactions on this Website

The information provided by you in order to make a purchase on a Hbc E-store is collected to process your online transaction, ship your item(s), administer our post-purchase survey and maintain the accuracy of your information. In order to protect you and Hbc from fraudulent transactions, Hbc may provide your transaction-related information to a reputable third party organization to perform an address verification. This address verification is intended to ensure that the "bill to" address that you provide matches your credit card address.

### Security

This website strives to protect your personal information. For security of transactions, we use the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts any information you send to us electronically. The encryption process protects your information, such as your credit card number, billing and shipping information by scrambling it before it is sent to us from your computer. Once the website receives your transmission, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our system. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while this website strives to protect your personal information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. 

### Unlawful Activities

This website reserves the right to co-operate with local, provincial, national and international authorities in investigations of improper or unlawful activities and this may require the disclosure of personal information. We may also report to other organizations about improper or unlawful user activities on this website and this reporting may include disclosure of personal information relating to those individuals conducting such improper or unlawful activities.

### Cookies

Your web browser places cookie files on your computer's hard drive. This website uses cookies to remember information you gave us so that you don't have to re-enter the information each time you visit this website. Cookies also help us understand which areas of our site are popular by showing us how you and others use our site. For more information about cookies and why they are used, please refer to our [cookies page](http://www.hbc.com/GlobalNav/cookiesen.asp).

### Web Beacons

This website uses electronic images called Web beacons, which are single-pixel (1 x1) or clear GIF images placed in the web page code. Web beacons are used for many of the same purposes as cookies, allowing us to understand the effectiveness of our marketing efforts and our site usability. Web beacons collect non-personally identifiable information on user traffic patterns, which we then analyze to improve the overall user experience on our website.

### About Any Other Information you send to this Website

Apart from information relating to shopping orders, Shop.Hbc.com Membership or eNewsletters, we do not collect or wish to receive any information or other materials from you through this website that may be considered personal, confidential or proprietary. All information and materials received (other than information concerning shopping orders, Shop.Hbc.com Membership or eNewsletters) will be considered to be non-confidential, and you will be deemed to have granted to this website an irrevocable license and consent to use, copy, display, and distribute such information and materials for any purpose whatsoever. This website will not use your name in connection with such information or materials without your prior consent.

### Hbc Rewards Privacy Information

### Use of your Personal Information

The information provided by you on your Hbc Rewards application, and other information that may be provided by you from time to time, as well as information about your transactions and redemptions, and any information captured whenever you provide your Hbc Rewards card number to Hbc and/or Hbc Rewards partners, is required by Hudson's Bay Company, its subsidiaries and affiliates (“Hbc”) to award and administer your Hbc Rewards account and maintain the accuracy of your information.

### Optional Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information

Any of the affiliated companies comprising Hbc or other organizations with which Hbc has marketing arrangements may have access to such information and may use it for the additional purposes of offering or communicating with you about other products and services. These communications may include notifications of sales, special events, store promotions and exclusive offers. Your consent to the access to and use of your personal information for these additional purposes is optional and not required as a condition of obtaining or using the Hbc Rewards card or collecting and redeeming Hbc Rewards points. If you do not wish your information to be accessed or used for these additional purposes, please contact the **Hbc Privacy Office** at **1-866-225-8251** , email us at [**privacy@hbc.com**](mailto:privacy@hbc.com) or write to **Hbc Privacy Office, P.O. Box 4135, Station A, Toronto, Ontario, M5W 3B7**. You also have the right to request to review the personal information Hbc has about you on file by contacting us, in writing, at the address above. For more information on Hbc’s Privacy Policy, please visit [www.hbc.ca/privacy](http://www.hbc.ca/privacy) or contact the Hbc Privacy Office.

### Hbc Credit Privacy Information

Personal information provided by you in your application for an Hbc credit card account (an “Account”), in connection with such Account or obtained subsequently from any source with your consent (collectively the “Information”), is collected and maintained by each of Capital One® and Hudson’s Bay Company and/or its affiliates (“Hbc”) in separate customer files (the “Files”) and: 

(a) used, from time to time, to obtain and exchange credit information from and with credit reporting agencies, credit references and other sources with whom you have or may expect to have financial dealings to underwrite and approve the Account or any subsequent account; 

(b) used to enter into, maintain and carry out the Account Agreement, including sharing Information between Capital One and Hbc in furtherance of the operation of the Account; 

(c) used by Hbc to establish and administer your Hbc Rewards account; 

(d) provided to a potential buyer as part of a sale of all or part of the portfolio of Accounts or of all or part of a business; 

(e) used to approve you for, and/or notify you of, other products or services that may be of interest to you (the “Additional Products”); and 

(f) may be disclosed to and used by third parties (“Third Parties”) to develop, enhance, market or provide other products and services that may be of interest to you (collectively the “Purposes”).

Capital One and/or Hbc may transfer some or all of the Information to external service providers who process the Information in furtherance of the Purposes or in accordance with applicable law. Your Files are currently managed from offices in Montreal, or Toronto. You have the right to access the Information and, if needed, to request a correction to the Information. If you wish to: 

  1. access the Information;   

  2. request correction to it; 
  3. request that we not approve/notify you for/of Additional Products; 
  4. request that we discontinue any disclosure of Information to Third Parties; 
  5. request that we discontinue maintenance and use of the Files for the Purposes (in which case we may be unable to continue to provide you with certain services); or 
  6. request written copies of our privacy policies (www.hbc.com/creditcard); 

you should call us toll-free at 1-866-225-8251 (Hbc Privacy Office).

##### 

### Gift Registry Privacy Information

### Use of your Personal Information

The information provided by you to create your gift registry is collected and used by Hudson's Bay Company and/or its affiliate Zellers Inc. (collectively, "Hbc") to publish your name and event date so that purchases can be made from your registry, follow up on any service matters, advise you of any fulfillment and delivery matters, allow you to add or delete items from your registry, manage the completion of your registry and maintain the accuracy of your information.

### Optional Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information

Hbc may wish to use the personal information you provided and the information collected to create your gift registry to offer or communicate with you about additional products and services provided by Hbc and other organizations with which Hbc has marketing arrangements. These communications may include notifications of sales, special events, store promotions and exclusive offers. Your consent to the use of your personal information for these additional purposes is optional and not required as a condition of creating a gift registry. If you do not wish Hbc to use this information for these additional purposes, please contact the Hbc Privacy Office. You also have the right to request to review the personal information Hbc has about you on file by contacting us, in writing, at the address above. For more information on Hbc's Privacy Policy, please contact the Hbc Privacy Office.

### Major Home Fashions Privacy Information

### Use of your Personal Information

The information provided by you to complete your sales receipt when you purchase major home fashions, eg. appliances, is collected and used by Hudson's Bay Company and its subsidiaries or affiliates (“Hbc”) and/or its service providers to ensure proper delivery of your purchase, follow up on any service matters, assist you with any manufacturer warranty claims, process extended warranty renewals and maintain the accuracy of your information.

### Optional Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information

Hbc may wish to use the personal information you provided and information resulting from your purchases to offer or communicate with you about additional products and services provided by Hbc and other organizations with which Hbc has marketing arrangements. These communications may include notifications of sales, special events, store promotions and exclusive offers. Your consent to the use of your personal information for these additional purposes is optional and not required as a condition of completing your purchase transaction. If you do not wish Hbc to use this information for these additional purposes, please contact the Hbc Privacy Office. You also have the right to request to review the personal information Hbc has about you on file by contacting us, in writing, at the address above. For more information on Hbc's Privacy Policy, please contact the Hbc Privacy Office.

### Clientelling Privacy Information

### Use of your Personal Information

The information provided by you to join our clientelling list is collected by Hudson's Bay Company, its subsidiaries and affiliates (“Hbc”) to administer our clientelling program and to maintain the accuracy of your information. If you wish to have your name removed from our clientelling list, please contact a sales manager at the store where you provided the information. If you wish to obtain more information on Hbc's Privacy Policy, please contact the Hbc Privacy Office. You also have the right to request to review the personal information Hbc has about you on file by contacting us, in writing, at the address above.

### Hbc Insurance Privacy Information

Hbc avantem insurance agency Inc. is a subsidiary of Hbc. It operates as "Hbc Insurance" and "Hbc Insurance Agency" ("we", "our", "us"). We promote and distribute a unique variety of insurance (and related) products, underwritten by some of Canada's leading insurance companies and other service providers. In doing this we need to collect, use, retain and sometimes disclose personal information. When we do collect, use, retain and disclose personal information, we are guided by the general privacy principles set out in _Hbc's Protection of Personal Information Principles_ and the specific personal information practices set out below. 

### Use of your Personal Information

The information provided by you to process requests for an insurance premium quote and/or to complete any applications for insurance, and other information which may be provided by you from time to time, is required by Hudson’s Bay Company to provide and administer requested products and services or to provide requested information. When an individual requests an insurance quote, inquires about insurance products (or related services), applies for coverage or becomes a policyholder, such individual is consenting to the collection, use, retention, and, if necessary, the disclosure of personal information. An individual is always free to decline or opt-out of this type of collection, use, retention and disclosure or personal information, but in that event, we will be unable to provide the requested services.

### Optional Use and Disclosure of your Personal Information

When you request a quote, inquire about insurance or related products, apply for coverage or become a policy holder through us, you become a customer of Hbc Insurance Agency. We may wish to use the personal information you provided to offer or communicate with you about upgraded and additional insurance and related products offered by us, our affiliates or other organizations with which we have marketing arrangements. These communications may include notifications of insurance (and related) products like auto, property, life and health insurance or other products which may be of interest to you. The information we disclose for such marketing purposes is limited to contact information and details of plan participation. It would not include health or lifestyle information, which would only be given to an insurance company in connection with an application for insurance. Your consent to use of your personal information for these additional marketing purposes is optional and is not required as a condition of obtaining an insurance premium quote, receiving information about insurance (and related) products, applying for insurance coverage or becoming a policyholder.

If you do not wish your information to be accessed or used for these additional purposes, please contact the **Hbc Insurance Agency Privacy Office** at **1-866-225-8251** , email us at **privacy@hbc.com** or write to **Hbc Insurance Agency Privacy Office, c/o Hbc Privacy Office, P.O. Box 4135, Station A, Toronto, Ontario M5W 3B7**. You also have the right to request to review the personal information Hbc has about you on file by contacting us, in writing, at the above address.

For more information on Hbc’s Privacy Policy, please visit www.hbc.ca/privacy or contact the Hbc Privacy Office.
